ELIA MARTINEZ

eliahaydeemartinez@gmail.com • 773.727.8552 • Chicago, IL

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliahmartinez • GitHub: https://github.com/EliaMart

Portfolio: https://eliamart.github.io/CssPortfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in medicine, education and simulation. Experience in emergency room settings and provide technical support for all simulation operations including; preparation, maintenance and repair of patient simulators (software and hardware). Resourceful and dynamic problem solver with the ability to collaborate and contribute with team members. Excellent time management and organizational skills.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University, Chicago, IL Certificate, Full Stack Web Developer

March 2022 - September 2022

University of Illinois at Chicago, *Chicago*, *IL* Bachelor of Science, Kinesiology *magna cum laude*

August 2011 - May 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, React, MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Postman, Insomnia, RESTful APIs, Server Side APIs, Bootstrap, GitHub, Git Bash/Terminal, Visual Studio Code

PROJECTS

So Fresh So Green

A Social Networking and E-Commerce application for plant lovers. Users have the ability to create, like and comment on posts, follow other users and purchase plants in the marketplace. In addition, create a page where they are able create a garden by adding plants to it.

Technology used: React, Apollo/GraphQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, JWT Authentication, Tailwind, AWS, Redux, Stripe, 3JS

Heroku Link: https://so-fresh-so-green-app.herokuapp.com/ • GitHub: https://github.com/So-Fresh-So-Green/so-fresh-so-green

Loc

An application that finds gender neutral and accessible public restrooms near you. This project uses Google Maps API to find bathrooms and save previously visited bathrooms.

Technology used: Javascript, Tailwind, ¡Query, Google Maps API, and Refuge Restrooms API.

Heroku Link: https://safe-haven-bathrooms.github.io/App/ • GitHub: https://github.com/Safe-Haven-Bathrooms/App

Employee Tracker

A Command Line Interface (CLI) Application created to allow for the management of a company's employee database. This application provides the ability to view and manage the departments, roles and employees in a company for organizational purposes.

Technology used: Node.js, inquirer, MySQL, Javascript, CLI • Github: https://qithub.com/EliaMart/employeeTracker

EXPERIENCE

Simulation Specialist

Northwestern Medicine, Chicago, IL

March 2019 - Present

- Designed and implemented 20 learning modules into the category one anesthesia resident curriculum
- Developed an online curriculum for residents and medical students during COVID-19 restrictions
- · Analyzed and presented data at the Society for Education in Anesthesia evaluating the competency of extubation in first year anesthesia residents
- Help create and launch a new curriculum for the Pulmonary Care Fellows

Emergency Room Technician

Swedish Hospital, Chicago, IL

July 2016 - March 2019

- · Assists in the maintenance and care of equipment, instruments, and supplies for over 20 patients in a shift
- Provides direct care as delegated by a Registered Nurse:
 - Vital Signs, respiratory care, urine collections, wound care, Stool collections, OB/GYN care, ENT care, Orthopedic care, code blue, Lumbar puncture care, procedures, obtains 12 Lead ECG